So,
그래서,
Aren't you too lazy to prepare breakfast?
아침 식사 준비하기엔 너무 게으르지 않나요?
but you don't have the habit?
그런데 버릇이 없지?
I do intermittent fasting.
나는 간헐적 단식을 하고 있다.
It's not that you failed
당신이 실패한 것이 아니다.
in having your license, Did you never bother to get it?
면허증을 가지고 있으면서, 굳이 그걸 얻으려고 애쓰신 적도 없으신가요?
Well,
글쎄,
It's my way of reducing carbon emissions.
그게 나의 줄이는 방법이야 탄소 배출.
So...
그래서...
It's not that you couldn't date, you avoided it.
연애를 못하는 게 아니라 피한 거다.
And why did you change your mind?
그리고 왜 마음을 바꾸셨나요?
You said you wanted to go slow.
천천히 가고 싶다고 하셨어요.
Anyone who hears you He'll think we slept together.
누가 들어도 그 사람은 우리가 같이 잤다고 생각할 거예요.
We don't sleep together, but under the same roof.
우리는 같이 자지 않는다. 하지만 같은 지붕 아래.
I think...
내 생각엔...
meet someone
누군가를 만나다
It involves knowing your space.
그것은 당신의 공간을 아는 것과 관련이 있습니다.
So,
그래서,
what do you think?
당신은 어떻게 생각하세요?
I expected to see sheet music everywhere,
어디에서나 악보를 볼 수 있을 거라 예상했는데,
that smelled like stale takeout
오래된 테이크아웃 냄새가 났어요
and that it reeked of cigarettes.
그리고 담배 냄새가 났어요.
I thought you would live like a zombie, that you would sleep during the day.
좀비처럼 살 줄 알았는데 당신이 낮에 잠을 잘 것이라고.
Are you disappointed?
실망하셨나요?
You broke my stereotype of the musician.
당신은 음악가에 대한 나의 고정관념을 깨뜨렸습니다.
After today's tea ceremony,
오늘 다과회가 끝난 후,
They will dine on Jeju silver scabbardfish.
그들은 제주은칼집을 먹습니다.
Then they will return to the hotel
그런 다음 그들은 호텔로 돌아갈 것입니다
for a massage at the spa.
스파에서 마사지를 받으러 가세요.
That's today's schedule.
그게 오늘의 일정이에요.
Unpack and rest in your rooms.
짐을 풀고 객실에서 휴식을 취하세요.
See you here at noon.
정오에 여기서 만나요.
See you later.
나중에 봐요.
- OK. - Gracias.
- 좋아요. - 그라시아스.
- Yeah.
- 응.
OK. Come on.
좋아요. 어서 해봐요.
Sorry.
죄송합니다.
- Do I have to go? - Yeah.
- 꼭 가야 하나요? - 응.
Sorry?
죄송합니다?
What do you mean?
무슨 뜻이에요?
To eat and to the excursion.
식사하고 소풍을 갑니다.
All of that is included in the rate.
그 모든 것이 요금에 포함되어 있습니다.
It's a top-notch package, you'll love it.
최고의 패키지입니다. 마음에 드실 겁니다.
I prefer to rest.
나는 휴식을 선호합니다.
In general, individual activities are not allowed,
일반적으로, 개인활동은 불가하며,
but if you stay, please, stay at the hotel.
하지만 계속 머무르신다면 제발 호텔에 묵으세요.
We can't risk it for you to go out and get hurt.
우리는 위험을 감수할 수 없습니다 네가 나가서 다칠까 봐.
[Happy 35th wedding anniversary]
[35번째 결혼기념일을 축하합니다]
Did you sleep with him?
그 사람이랑 잤어?
You distanced yourself and played hard to get.
당신은 거리를 두고 열심히 노력했습니다.
We just sleep.
우리는 그냥 자요.
I swear, we did just that. We sleep and nothing else.
맹세컨대, 우리는 바로 그렇게 했습니다. 우리는 자고 다른 것은 없습니다.
Without touching? Did they just sleep?
만지지 않고? 방금 잠을 잤나요?
- Yes. - Is that possible?
- 예. - 그게 가능해요?
We decided to go slow.
우리는 천천히 가기로 결정했습니다.
Go slow?
천천히 가볼까?
The cold Seo Jun Kyung and the poor musician
차가운 서준경과 불쌍한 음악가
Did you agree to postpone sex?
성관계를 연기하기로 동의하셨나요?
Well,
글쎄,
Anyway, that's how it ends.
아무튼 그렇게 끝납니다.
Is this something a gynecologist should say?
이게 산부인과 의사가 말해야 하는 건가요?
Should we encourage sex?
섹스를 장려해야 할까?
There are many things you can postpone, but just that?
미룰 수 있는 일이 많지만, 그런데 그것뿐이야?
They are the laziest couple in the world.
그들은 세상에서 가장 게으른 커플이다.
So,
그래서,
what did they do all night?
그들은 밤새도록 무엇을 했나요?
Well...
음...
we drank
우리는 마셨다
and we talk.
그리고 우리는 이야기를 나눕니다.
He is my polar opposite,
그는 나와 정반대입니다.
that's all I know.
내가 아는 것은 그게 전부입니다.
But somehow,
하지만 왠지
that difference didn't bother me that much like I thought it would happen.
그 차이는 별로 신경쓰이지 않았습니다 내가 생각했던 것처럼.
They did it, didn't they?
그들이 해냈지, 그렇지?
Would you believe it if someone told you?
누군가가 당신에게 말한다면 당신은 그것을 믿을 수 있습니까?
You can't sleep at home, and you slept like a baby in his?
집에서는 잠을 못 자고, 그런데 당신은 그의 침대에서 아기처럼 잤나요?
Didn't they do anything else?
그들은 다른 짓을 하지 않았나요?
It's true.
사실이에요.
How did I sleep so well
내가 어떻게 그렇게 잘 잤지?
in someone else's house?
다른 사람 집에?
It doesn't matter,
그것은 중요하지 않습니다.
don't tell anyone.
아무에게도 말하지 마세요.
As if there was something to say.
마치 할 말이 있는 것처럼.
Do you know something?
당신은 뭔가를 알고 있나요?
That?
저것?
Dr. Hong didn't have lunch, not because I'm on a diet,
홍박사는 점심을 먹지 않았고, 다이어트 중이라서가 아니라
but because she had a fight with her boyfriend.
하지만 그녀가 남자친구와 싸웠기 때문이에요.
Oh really?
오, 진짜?
How barbaric.
얼마나 야만적입니까.
There's that smile.
그 미소가 있습니다.
Even though it's a little uncomfortable, days have passed.
조금 불편하기도 하지만, 며칠이 지났습니다.
Let's eat!
먹자!
- Let's go together.
- 같이 가자.
Hurry up.
서둘러요.
I don't have to rehearse today. Where are you?
오늘은 리허설을 할 필요가 없어요. 당신은 어디에 있나요?
Why are you ignoring my messages?
왜 내 메시지를 무시하는 거죠?
You don't answer me when I call you either.
내가 불러도 너도 대답 안 해.
Why are you angry?
왜 화가 났나요?
I'm not angry.
나는 화를 내지 않습니다.
So, I'm leaving.
그래서 나는 떠난다.
Wait!
기다리다!
Yeah,
응,
I'm angry.
나는 화가 났다.
What's happening? Why are you upset?
무슨 일이야? 왜 화가 났나요?
Who is that guy?
그 사람은 누구입니까?
Who?
WHO?
That guy.
그 사람.
He looks like a scoundrel.
그는 악당처럼 보입니다.
Post photos of yourself on all your social networks.
자신의 사진을 게시하세요. 모든 소셜 네트워크에서.
Boom Jun?
붐 준?
How cute you are.
당신은 정말 귀엽습니다.
Come here.
이리 오세요.
What are you doing?
뭐하세요?
Look what I do.
내가 뭘하는지보세요.
"He is the light of my eyes."
"그는 내 눈의 빛이다."
I published it.
나는 그것을 출판했다.
Are you happy now?
당신은 지금 행복합니까?
- You are, right? - No.
- 그렇죠? - 아니.
Of course you are!
물론이죠!
Estonia?
에스토니아?
Have you been there?
거기 가본 적 있어?
Yes.
예.
When? With who?
언제? 누구와?
Again with your suspicions.
다시 한 번 의심해 보세요.
two years ago, I went with my team for a show.
2년 전, 나는 쇼를 위해 우리 팀과 함께 갔다.
I see.
알겠어요.
First, let's go to the most beautiful restaurant of the historic center,
먼저 가장 아름다운 레스토랑으로 가자 역사 중심지의,
I invite everyone I know for the first round.
내가 아는 모든 사람을 초대합니다 첫 번째 라운드를 위해.
Yes.
예.
Then, we go to the most popular club in the center for the second round.
그 다음에는 중앙에 있는 가장 인기 있는 클럽으로 이동합니다. 두 번째 라운드를 위해.
Yes.
예.
And finally,
그리고 마지막으로,
We go back to the hotel, just you and me,
너와 나 둘만 호텔로 돌아가
for a suggestive third round.
암시적인 세 번째 라운드를 위해.
What's that?
그게 뭐야?
Well? That?
잘? 저것?
But seriously,
하지만 진지하게,
Why do you celebrate your birthday so far away?
왜 이렇게 먼 곳에서 생일을 축하하나요?
Well,
글쎄,
It's my dream.
내 꿈이에요.
Heavens.
천국.
Hey.
여기요.
Do you want something else besides that?
그 외에 다른 것을 원하시나요?
Tell me.
말해 주세요.
If I tell you,
내가 말하면,
will you do it?
당신은 그것을 할 것인가?
No!
아니요!
Hello, dad.
안녕하세요, 아빠.
Hello.
안녕하세요.
I guess I shouldn't have come.
아무래도 오지 말았어야 했을 것 같아요.
I should have listened to Jun Seo.
서준이의 말을 들었어야 했는데.
Did you go on a trip?
여행을 가셨나요?
I'm sure you don't understand me, do you?
당신은 내 말을 이해하지 못하시겠죠?
With everything that is happening.
현재 일어나고 있는 모든 일들
I felt like doing it anyway.
그래도 하고 싶은 마음이 들었습니다.
I understand you.
나는 당신을 이해합니다.
Have you left work yet?
아직 퇴근 안하셨나요?
I'm on it.
나는 그것에 있습니다.
I wonder if Jun Seo is eating.
준서는 밥을 먹고 있는지 궁금해요.
- A party at home? - Yes.
- 집에서 파티요? - 예.
I don't want a boring birthday party in a rented room.
지루한 생일파티는 싫어 임대 방에서.
I want a real birthday party.
나는 진짜 생일 파티를 원한다.
But my house is very small.
하지만 우리 집은 매우 작습니다.
What do you think?
어떻게 생각하나요?
Your dad is away, So there's no one home, right?
네 아버지는 부재중이야. 그럼 집에 아무도 없겠죠?
What's happening?
무슨 일이야?
Don't you like the idea?
아이디어가 마음에 들지 않나요?
It's just...
그것은 단지 ...
I don't know if we should do it there.
거기서 해야 할지 모르겠어요.
My mom passed away recently.
최근에 엄마가 돌아가셨어요.
Do you know the situation I'm going through? at this moment.
내가 겪고 있는 상황을 아시나요? 이 순간.
Yeah?
응?
He's not feeling well either. and he will stay alone at home.
그 사람도 몸이 좋지 않아요. 그리고 그는 집에 혼자 있을 것이다.
It's not pleasant to eat alone.
혼자 먹기엔 불편해요.
You have to have dinner too.
너도 저녁 먹어야 해.
Yes, and you, dad.
네, 그리고 당신도요, 아빠.
I wanted to know
나는 알고 싶었다
if you have been able to rest.
쉴 수 있었다면.
Yes, thanks.
네, 고마워요.
I asked at the restaurant, They told me you didn't go to eat.
식당에 물어보니 밥 먹으러 안 갔다고 하더군요.
Eating alone didn't seem right to me.
혼자 밥을 먹는 것은 나에게 적합하지 않은 것 같았다.
That's right,
그렇죠.
That's why people gather in groups.
그래서 사람들은 집단으로 모인다.
I brought you abalone gimbap.
전복김밥을 가져왔습니다.
It's for you.
그것은 당신을 위한 것입니다.
Abalone gimbap?
전복김밥?
Tomorrow you will be with us all day.
내일 당신은 하루 종일 우리와 함께 있을 것입니다.
I already noticed.
나는 이미 알아 차렸다.
Yes, it should be fine.
예, 괜찮습니다.
OK.
좋아요.
I'll put it together and ship it tomorrow morning.
내일 오전에 정리해서 발송해 드리겠습니다.
They call themselves writers,
그들은 스스로를 작가라고 부른다.
but the spelling mistakes They are not something to brag about.
근데 맞춤법이 틀려 그것들은 자랑할 것이 아닙니다.
Incredible.
믿을 수 없는.
What pain!
정말 고통스럽습니다!
Hey.
여기요.
I'm sorry, but I have to work.
미안하지만 일을 해야 해요.
I can't eat with you.
나는 당신과 함께 식사할 수 없습니다.
Have you been to Estonia?
에스토니아에 가본 적이 있나요?
I would like to go to the Baltic States.
나는 발트해 연안 국가에 가고 싶습니다.
Someone who will go to Estonia,
에스토니아에 갈 사람,
someone who is in Jeju...
제주에 계시는 분이..
By the way,
그건 그렇고,
today is perfect
오늘은 완벽해
to have a party
파티를 하려고
on your roof
당신의 지붕에
What are you taking about?
당신은 무엇을 복용하고 있습니까?
I feel like I'm the person who is loneliest in the world.
내가 그 사람인 것 같은 느낌이 들어요 세상에서 가장 외로운 사람.
When I'm alone, I feel this way because there is no one.
내가 혼자 있을 때, 사람이 없어서 이런 느낌이 드네요.
And when I'm with someone, also, because I fear ending up alone.
그리고 누군가와 함께 있을 때, 그리고 결국엔 혼자가 되는 게 두렵기 때문이다.
With money or without it,
돈이 있든 없든,
loneliness is the same.
외로움도 마찬가지다.
Is there anything fairer than loneliness?
외로움보다 더 공평한 것이 있을까요?
No,
아니요,
It's unfair.
불공평해요.
I feel more alone than others, even if it's just.
나는 다른 사람들보다 외로움을 더 많이 느낀다. 비록 그것이 단지.
Nobody understands me.
아무도 나를 이해하지 못합니다.
I'll leave early.
일찍 떠날게요.
Where are you going?
어디 가세요?
- Sorry? - For her, it's the first day.
- 죄송합니다? - 그녀에게는 첫날이에요.
You have an appointment.
약속이 있어요.
- It's a secret. - Sure, a secret.
- 비밀이에요. - 물론이죠, 비밀이에요.
Good luck.
행운을 빌어요.
- Couldn't you keep the secret even for a day? - Can!
- 하루라도 비밀을 지킬 수 없었나요? - 할 수 있다!
Don't start quietly and let it fade away.
조용히 시작하지 말고 서서히 사라지도록 놔두십시오.
This time, even if you're embarrassed, do it right.
이번에는 부끄럽더라도 제대로 해보세요.
- Aunt. - Very good.
- 이모. - 아주 좋아요.
Aunt.
이모.
Come see us with your boyfriend.
남자친구와 함께 우리를 만나러 오세요.
Your relationship is no longer yours alone.
당신의 관계는 더 이상 당신만의 것이 아닙니다.
Take responsibility, okay?
책임을 져라, 알았지?
Why are you looking at me like that?
왜 나를 그렇게 보는 거죠?
What brings you here? Without warning.
무슨 일로 여기까지 왔나요? 경고 없이.
- It's daytime. Can't I come in? - Dad is not at home.
- 낮이에요. 들어갈 수는 없나요? - 아빠는 집에 없어요.
He is traveling.
그는 여행 중입니다.
I already know.
나는 이미 알고 있다.
To the side.
옆으로.
Did you eat?
식사하셨나요?
Is this what you call grieving your way?
이것이 당신의 방식으로 슬픔을 느끼는 것입니까?
- It's just... - Don't say anything.
- 그냥... - 아무 말도 하지 마세요.
I know what you're going to say,
나는 당신이 무슨 말을 하려는지 알아요.
and it's probably fine.
아마 괜찮을 거예요.
Thank you.
감사합니다.
Let's eat.
먹자.
You got a message.
메시지를 받았습니다.
What does it say?
그것은 무엇을 말합니까?
It's your neighbor's.
그것은 당신의 이웃의 것입니다.
"Jun Kyung, today is our first day."
"준경 씨, 오늘이 우리 첫 날이에요."
"Especially during the day." It's all I see.
"특히 낮에는요." 내가 보는 전부입니다.
Here it is.
여기 있습니다.
Congratulations on the first day.
첫날을 축하합니다.
Dad really knows how to make soup. It is rich and substantial.
아빠는 수프 만드는 법을 정말 잘 알아요. 그것은 풍부하고 실질적입니다.
It's quite conservative.
상당히 보수적이에요.
He must have cooked it carefully, without anything strange.
이상한 점 없이 조심스럽게 요리한 게 틀림없었다.
Yes.
예.
Do you know?
당신은 알고 있나요?
The message that came to me...
나에게 온 메시지..
it's nothing...
아무것도 아니야...
- Don't say it. - That?
- 말하지 마세요. - 저것?
I know what you're going to say,
나는 당신이 무슨 말을 하려는지 알아요.
and it's probably fine.
아마 괜찮을 거예요.
Let's eat.
먹자.
Thank you.
감사합니다.
How inopportune.
얼마나 부적절한가.
What a shame.
정말 부끄러운 일입니다.
Yes, Do Hyun.
응, 도현아.
What a nice place.
정말 좋은 곳이에요.
What work do you do here?
여기서 어떤 일을 하시나요?
Here?
여기?
Do you want to know
알고 싶나요?
what job
무슨 직업
do I do in this place?
내가 이런 곳에서 하는 걸까?
That?
저것?
It's...
그것은 ...
Yes.
그렇습니다.
That coffee commercial.
그 커피광고.
It's the sequel and comes out next week.
속편이고 다음주에 나오네요.
My music is still a draft,
내 음악은 아직 초안이고,
but I put it in a beautiful video.
하지만 아름다운 영상에 담았습니다.
It's the first time I invite someone to my studio.
누군가를 초대하는 건 처음이에요 내 스튜디오로.
When you know me better,
당신이 나를 더 잘 알게 되면,
You're not going to be disappointed, right?
실망하지 않을 거에요, 그렇죠?
Until now, no.
지금까지는 그렇지 않았습니다.
What do you think of those two?
그 두 가지에 대해 어떻게 생각하시나요?
They seem lonely.
그들은 외로워 보입니다.
Well...
음...
I can convert them
나는 그것들을 변환할 수 있어요
in a sad couple
슬픈 커플 속에서
who senses a breakup.
이별을 느끼는 사람.
Or if I want, in a couple
아니면 내가 원하면 커플로
that's just starting to come out
그게 이제 막 나오기 시작하는 거야
and feel butterflies in your stomach.
뱃속에서 나비를 느껴보세요.
As?
처럼?
I have that power.
나에겐 그런 힘이 있다.
Oh really?
오, 진짜?
It changes the vibe a lot.
분위기가 많이 바뀌네요.
what will happen
무슨 일이 일어날까요?
with those two now?
지금 그 둘이랑?
Do you remember that...
그거 기억하시나요...
we agreed...
우리는 동의했다...
go slow, right?
천천히 가, 응?
Yes.
예.
Did you sleep well?
잘 잤어요?
Yes!
예!
Will you stay locked up today too?
오늘도 갇혀있을 거야?
It's a beautiful day!
아름다운 날이에요!
- What an amazing place! - I love it!
- 정말 놀라운 곳이에요! - 정말 좋아요!
There is little left to arrive. Hold on a little longer.
도착이 얼마 남지 않았습니다. 조금만 더 참으세요.
Are you OK?
괜찮으세요?
Keep going.
계속하세요.
What happened?
무슨 일이에요?
- Why do you stop? - My pants tore.
- 왜 멈추나요? - 바지가 찢어졌어요.
No!
아니요!
Give me that, I'll take care of it.
그거 나한테 줘, 내가 처리할게.
Careful!
주의 깊은!
Thank you.
감사합니다.
I think that jacket
내 생각엔 그 재킷이
yes it helped.
응, 도움이 됐어.
Thank goodness you brought it.
가져다주셔서 감사합니다.
Thank you very much, seriously.
진심으로 감사드립니다.
- Don't sit there! Burn! - Burn!
- 거기 앉지 마세요! 불타다! - 불타다!
It's very bad.
매우 나쁩니다.
The owner can't do that.
주인이 그러면 안 돼요.
How can you change your move-in date? When do you feel like it?
입주일은 어떻게 변경할 수 있나요? 언제 그런 기분이 드나요?
That's the situation, what can I do?
그런 상황인데 어떻게 해야 하나요?
I must be understanding.
나는 이해하고 있어야합니다.
They even covered the furniture deposit. and large objects.
그들은 심지어 가구 보증금도 덮었습니다. 그리고 큰 물체.
There's not much left,
얼마 남지 않았네요,
that's all.
그게 다야.
Everything is ready.
모든 것이 준비되었습니다.
Don't bother
귀찮게 하지 마세요
to come back later.
나중에 다시 오려고.
It will be faster if we do it together.
함께 하면 더 빨라질 거예요.
Someone else will arrive in a while, We will finish what is left together.
조금 있으면 다른 사람이 올 거야. 남은 일은 함께 마무리하겠습니다.
Listen,
들어봐,
Could you bring us something cool to drink?
시원한 마실 것을 가져다 주시겠어요?
What do I buy?
나는 무엇을 사나요?
Whatever.
무엇이든.
- Be careful with traffic. - Clear.
- 교통에 주의하세요. - 분명한.
They changed the date of the move, so it will stay in someone's house.
이사 날짜가 바뀌었는데, 그래서 그것은 누군가의 집에 머물게 될 것입니다.
Won't it be uncomfortable?
불편하진 않겠지?
For whom?
누구를 위해?
For him?
그에게?
Or for your feelings?
아니면 당신의 감정 때문에?
Knowing that he is leaving suddenly makes me uneasy.
그 사람이 갑자기 떠난다는 걸 알면 불안해지거든요.
Are you leaving the country?
출국하시나요?
Are they sending him on a mission?
그 사람을 임무에 보내는 건가요?
Should I tell him to stay at my house?
그 사람에게 내 집에 머물라고 말해야 할까?
Are you crazy?
제정신이에요?
You've known him for a few days, and do you already want to live together?
당신은 그 사람을 알고 지낸 지 며칠 됐어요. 그런데 벌써 같이 살고 싶나요?
We are not going to live together,
같이 살 것도 아니고,
It will be temporary, until you move.
이사하기 전까지는 일시적입니다.
That's too much. They haven't slept together yet.
너무 많아요. 그들은 아직 함께 자지 않았습니다.
That?
저것?
Did you sleep with him?
그 사람이랑 잤어?
Even so,
그래도
you don't want
당신은 원하지 않는다
share everything from the beginning, right?
처음부터 모든 걸 공유하지?
Seem to you?
당신에게 보인다?
Didn't you want to go slowly?
천천히 가고 싶지 않으셨나요?
Bathroom habits, snoring,
화장실 습관, 코골이,
your face without makeup, the farts you fart...
화장하지 않은 너의 얼굴, 방귀, 너 방귀..
There is nowhere to hide.
숨을 곳이 없습니다.
In this instance, you should just show your charming side.
이 경우, 당신의 매력적인 면만 보여주면 돼요.
You are using a risky tactic.
위험한 전술을 사용하고 있습니다.
Yes, right?
응, 그렇지?
It seems that his assistant arrived.
그의 조수가 도착한 것 같습니다.
You can get off.
하차하시면 됩니다.
That?
저것?
What's happening?
무슨 일이 일어나고 있나요?
A woman came to help him.
한 여자가 그를 돕기 위해 왔습니다.
That?
저것?
He has longer hair than mine
그 사람은 나보다 머리가 더 길어요
and it is thinner.
그리고 더 얇아졌어요.
Does that mean he's staying with a woman?
그 말은 그가 여자와 함께 지내고 있다는 뜻인가요?
Just as I thought, he is a free soul unleashed.
내 생각대로 그는 해방된 자유로운 영혼이다.
I have to cut.
잘라야 해요.
Looks like your helper has arrived.
도우미가 도착한 것 같습니다.
Yes.
예.
He went to get the last box.
그는 마지막 상자를 가지러 갔다.
They must know each other very well.
그들은 서로를 아주 잘 알아야 합니다.
He is the person with whom I have the most confidence.
그는 내가 가장 신뢰하는 사람이다.
We've been through everything,
우리는 모든 것을 겪었습니다.
for the good and the bad.
좋은 것과 나쁜 것을 위해.
Do Hyun.
도현.
Yes.
예.
So...
그래서...
Well...
음...
I brought you coffee.
커피를 가져왔습니다.
Gracias.
그라시아스.
Wait.
기다리다.
Do you want to stay at my house?
우리 집에 머물고 싶니?
Of course...
물론...
Bueno...
부에노...
I say...
내 말은 ...
is close to move,
이사가 가까워요,
the place is spacious,
장소는 넓고,
y...
와이...
your studio is also nearby.
당신의 스튜디오도 근처에 있어요.
OK,
좋아요,
I accept.
동의합니다.
Oh really?
오, 진짜?
I will introduce them.
나는 그들을 소개할 것이다.
This is Woo Jung Hoon.
우정훈입니다.
I present to you
나는 당신에게 선물한다
a Seo Jun Kyung,
서준경,
my girlfriend
내 여자친구
Hello,
안녕하세요,
Nice to meet you.
만나서 반가워요.
So,
그래서,
did you believe
당신은 믿었나요?
What was a woman?
여자란 무엇이었는가?
What image do you have of me?
당신은 나에 대해 어떤 이미지를 갖고 있나요?
I'm not like Hollywood musicians.
나는 할리우드 뮤지션과는 다릅니다.
It's just that...
단지 그게...
he has very silky hair
그 사람 머리가 아주 부드러워요
and thin legs.
그리고 얇은 다리.
I should invite him to lunch sometime.
언젠가 그를 점심에 초대해야겠어요.
We should eat too.
우리도 먹어야 해요.
It's moving day,
이사하는 날인데,
Do we have the number of a Chinese restaurant?
중국집 전화번호는 있나요?
Heavens!
천국!
Thank you.
감사합니다.
You got jealous.
질투심이 생겼어요.
Hang on a minute.
잠깐만요.
Hello?
안녕하세요?
I see.
알겠어요.
How often are the contractions?
수축은 얼마나 자주 발생합니까?
Then, we won't need oxytocin.
그러면 옥시토신이 필요하지 않습니다.
I'll go right now.
지금 바로 갈게요.
Hello, Sol.
안녕, 솔.
You said four people, right?
4명이라고 하셨죠?
Five?
다섯?
It's ok no problem.
괜찮아요 문제없어요
I already took care of everything,
이미 다 처리했는데,
so come.
그러니 오세요.
Everything ready.
모든 것이 준비되었습니다.
Did you fix the pants?
바지는 고쳤나요?
You didn't know that, did you?
당신은 그것을 몰랐죠?
I stay next to your room.
나는 당신 방 옆에 있어요.
One moment.
잠시만요.
Here you go.
여기요.
Thank you so much.
매우 감사합니다.
The wind in Jeju
제주의 바람
It's not a joke.
농담이 아닙니다.
Yes, I fixed the pants.
응, 바지는 내가 고쳤어.
Luckily, They had a sewing kit in the lobby.
다행히도, 로비에 바느질 도구가 있었어요.
Apparently, you are very skilled.
분명히 당신은 매우 숙련된 것 같습니다.
Not really.
설마.
I just made sure
방금 확인했어요
that it looked good so that it wouldn't be noticed.
눈에 띄지 않을 정도로 좋아 보이도록.
What will you do for dinner?
저녁 식사로 무엇을 할 건가요?
I'll find something quick and eat here.
빨리 뭔가 찾아서 여기서 먹을게요.
Eat calmly, every meal matters.
침착하게 식사하세요. 모든 식사가 중요합니다.
Try the Italian restaurant in the Ocean Wing.
이탈리안 레스토랑을 맛보세요 오션윙에서.
It's pretty good.
꽤 좋습니다.
Do you want us to have dinner together?
우리 같이 저녁 먹을래요?
I am also alone in my free time.
나는 또한 자유 시간에 혼자입니다.
I'm not used to using cutlery.
나는 수저를 사용하는 데 익숙하지 않습니다.
I saw you booked
예약하신 걸 봤어요
the yacht ride for tomorrow.
내일 요트 타러 가.
Yes.
예.
I signed up because my wife he would have loved it.
아내 때문에 가입했어요 그는 그것을 좋아했을 것입니다.
But recently...
그런데 최근...
passed away.
세상을 떠났다.
I see.
알겠어요.
I wish we could have come together,
같이 왔으면 좋았을 텐데,
but it was not possible.
그러나 그것은 불가능했습니다.
Still, you came.
그래도 오셨군요.
That's what matters.
그것이 중요한 것입니다.
♪ Happy birthday to you ♪
♪ 생일 축하해 ♪
♪ Happy birthday to Sol ♪
♪ 솔님 생일 축하해요 ♪ ♪ 솔의 생일을 축하합니다 ♪
No, please! Don't do that!
아니, 제발! 그러지 마세요!
One moment.
잠시만요.
Wait.
기다리다.
What do they do?
그들은 무엇을 합니까?
Please get out of here.
여기서 나가주세요.
Alright. Let's go.
괜찮은. 갑시다.
They won't allow it.
그들은 그것을 허용하지 않을 것입니다.
You can't smoke here.
여기서는 담배를 피울 수 없습니다.
They have to go out.
그들은 나가야 합니다.
What's the matter?
무슨 일이야?
Are you going to vomit?
토할거야?
Thank you very much
정말 감사합니다
for today.
오늘은.
Tell me...
말해봐...
You didn't come with bad intentions, right?
나쁜 의도로 오신 건 아니죠?
Sorry?
죄송합니다?
That would worry me.
그게 걱정이 될 것 같아요.
I am a person of faith.
나는 믿음의 사람입니다.
So,
그래서,
there is nothing to worry about.
걱정할 것이 없습니다.
Has something like this happened here?
여기서 이런 일이 일어났나요?
Sorry?
죄송합니다?
I mean if they come to end everything.
내 말은, 그들이 모든 것을 끝내게 된다면 말이야.
Yes, there was a case quite a long time ago,
네, 꽤 오래전에 사건이 있었습니다.
on the Camino de Santiago.
카미노 데 산티아고에서.
I had a great time.
나는 즐거운 시간을 보냈습니다.
Me too.
저도요.
Call me when you're done.
완료되면 전화주세요.
Hello.
안녕하세요.
I've finished now.
이제 끝났어요.
You took too long.
시간이 너무 오래 걸렸어요.
That baby owes everything to his mother.
그 아이는 엄마에게 모든 빚을 지고 있어요.
The birth was exhausting.
출산은 지쳤습니다.
I'm exhausted and starving.
나는 지치고 배고프다.
Hurry up.
서둘러요.
I haven't eaten yet,
아직 안 먹어봤는데,
I was waiting for you for dinner.
나는 저녁 식사를 위해 당신을 기다리고 있었습니다.
Haven't you eaten yet?
아직 식사 안 하셨나요?
You should have gone ahead.
당신은 먼저 갔어야 했어요.
True, there is nothing to eat at home.
사실 집에 먹을 게 하나도 없어요.
How about those noodles? What did we miss earlier?
그 국수는 어때요? 우리는 이전에 무엇을 놓쳤습니까?
I think it's great.
나는 그것이 훌륭하다고 생각한다.
Hurry up.
서둘러요.
OK.
좋아요.
[The neighbor]
[이웃]
[Do Hyun]
[도현]
Damn, I'm hopeless.
젠장, 난 절망적이야
Thank you.
감사합니다.
Go ahead, I'll stay here.
어서 가세요. 저는 여기 남겠습니다.
[Please make this work]
[이런 일을 해주세요]
"You can survive loneliness,
"외로움을 이겨낼 수 있습니다.
but still,
하지만 그래도
you need someone to tell you
말해 줄 사람이 필요해요
that it's okay to be alone."
혼자 있어도 괜찮습니다."
Honoré de Balzac.
오노레 드 발자크.
I'm sorry.
미안해요.
How is your night going?
오늘 밤은 잘 보내고 계시나요?
If you feel alone now,
지금 외로움을 느낀다면
I can tell you.
말씀드릴 수 있습니다.
It would be 9000 won.
9000원이겠죠.
Being alone is okay.
혼자 있어도 괜찮습니다.
Did you arrive?
도착하셨나요?
You're hungry, aren't you?
배고프지 않나요?
I called the washing machine technician.
세탁기 기술자에게 전화했어요.
It was broken.
고장났습니다.
It was another place.
다른 곳이었습니다.
My house, usually,
우리 집은 보통
it was gloomy,
어두웠어요
but finally he seemed to be happy...
하지만 마침내 그는 행복해 보였어요...
What are you doing?
뭐하는 거야?
-...to see me. - Good! Good decision.
-...나를 만나러. - 좋아요! 좋은 결정이군요.
Go wash.
가서 씻으세요.
How are you doing?
어떻게 지내세요?
Delicious.
맛있는.
Just "delicious"?
그냥 "맛있다"?
Nothing else?
다른 건 없나요?
What else?
또 뭐야?
Well...
음...
Doesn't it have anything that touches your heart?
마음에 와닿는 내용은 없나요?
Are you asking for compliments?
칭찬을 구하는 건가요?
If we were facing another dish, yes,
만약 우리가 다른 요리를 마주하고 있다면, 그렇습니다.
but the curry is different.
하지만 카레는 다르다.
It is a comforting dish.
마음이 편안해지는 요리입니다.
Because?
왜냐하면?
Curry is my ideal food.
카레는 나의 이상적인 음식이다.
When I didn't have a penny, I was cold and struggling as a musician,
한 푼도 없었을 때, 음악가로서 차갑고 힘들었지만,
I had a 1000 won curry package,
카레 1000원짜리 포장이었는데,
I only added potatoes and onions,
저는 감자와 양파만 넣었어요
and prepared a large quantity.
그리고 대량으로 준비했습니다.
To the second
두 번째로
and on the third day,
그리고 셋째날,
tasted more intense
더 강렬한 맛이 났어요
and, in some ways, even better.
그리고 어떤 면에서는 훨씬 더 좋습니다.
As if it got better overnight.
밤새 좋아진 것처럼.
This is how I created my fantasy.
이것이 내가 환상을 창조한 방법이다.
What fantasy?
무슨 환상?
one night,
어느 날 밤,
I come home exhausted
나는 지쳐서 집에 온다
for no apparent reason.
뚜렷한 이유 없이.
There she is, with her apron on,
거기 그녀는 앞치마를 두른 채,
stirring the curry.
카레를 저어줍니다.
That aroma invades
그 향기가 침입해
the entire apartment.
아파트 전체.
Well...
음...
It's a pretty simple fantasy.
꽤 단순한 환상이다.
But it doesn't end there.
하지만 여기서 끝나지 않습니다.
He has his apron on
그 사람은 앞치마를 입고 있어요
and nothing more.
그리고 그 이상은 없습니다.
- Pervert! - You will, right?
- 변태! - 그럴 거예요, 그렇죠?
- I? - Yes.
- 나? - 예.
You are crazy!
당신은 미쳤어요!
Please make my fantasy come true.
내 환상을 현실로 만들어주세요.
It's ridiculous.
말도 안 돼요.
I haven't seen you laugh like that until now.
나는 지금까지 당신이 그렇게 웃는 것을 본 적이 없습니다.
You accompanied me so I wouldn't be locked up
내가 갇히지 않게 동행해 주었지
playing hard to get, right?
얻기 위해 열심히 놀고 있는 거죠, 그렇죠?
Being a guide must be very hard.
가이드가 되는 것은 매우 어려울 것입니다.
Not at all.
별말씀을요.
I travel for free as much as I want.
나는 내가 원하는 만큼 무료로 여행한다.
And not only that, they also pay me.
그뿐만 아니라 그들은 나에게도 돈을 지불합니다.
Also, the yacht ride It is the most expensive excursion in the package.
또한 요트를 타면서 패키지 중 가장 비싼 여행입니다.
Oh really?
오, 진짜?
Being in such a beautiful place It makes me think of my husband.
이렇게 아름다운 곳에 있으면 남편 생각이 나네요.
We were never able to take a yacht trip together.
우리는 함께 요트 여행을 갈 수 없었습니다.
They can still do it.
그들은 여전히 ​​​​할 수 있습니다.
They will have the opportunity.
그들에게는 기회가 있을 것입니다.
I lost my husband ten years ago.
나는 10년 전에 남편을 잃었습니다.
This doesn't know at all
이건 전혀 모르겠어
to what I eat in Seoul.
서울에서 먹는 것.
Also try the turban snail.
또한 터번 달팽이를 시험해보십시오.
They were taken out by the haenyeo, the traditional divers here.
해녀에게 빼앗겼고, 여기 전통 다이버들이 있어요.
"Very salty."
"매우 짜다."
"Too spicy."
"너무 매워요."
My wife scolded me for it all the time.
내 아내는 항상 나를 꾸짖었습니다.
Now that the one who ate healthy is no longer here,
이제 건강하게 먹던 그 사람이 없으니까,
It's funny how it works.
그것이 어떻게 작동하는지 재밌습니다.
Look there.
저기 보세요.
Do you see that group?
그 그룹 보이시나요?
Yes.
예.
Let this stay between us, okay?
우리 사이에 두고 보자, 알았지?
Their treatment is somewhat different.
그들의 치료법은 다소 다릅니다.
Different how?
어떻게 다른가요?
It's the Delete It From Mind package.
그것은 마인드에서 삭제(Delete It From Mind) 패키지입니다.
- Delete it from your mind? - Silence.
- 마음에서 삭제하시겠습니까? - 고요.
They look happy,
그들은 행복해 보인다,
but they are going through a bad time.
하지만 그들은 힘든 시간을 보내고 있어요.
They chose this
그들은 이것을 선택했습니다
just to forget about it for a while.
그냥 잠시 잊어버리려고요.
When they return home,
그들이 집에 돌아올 때,
They will return to reality, everything will remain exactly the same.
그들은 현실로 돌아올 것이고, 모든 것이 정확히 동일하게 유지됩니다.
But while they're here, They want to forget everything.
하지만 그들이 여기 있는 동안, 그들은 모든 것을 잊고 싶어합니다.
That's why
그렇기 때문에
They all wear the same hats.
그들은 모두 같은 모자를 쓰고 있습니다.
- Exact. - I understand.
- 정확한. - 이해합니다.
Look.
바라보다.
Do you see that couple
저 커플 보이시나요?
of light blue shirts?
하늘색 셔츠?
The ones there?
거기 있는 사람들?
- Those who take photos. - Yes.
- 사진을 찍으시는 분들. - 예.
They have been married for five years.
그들은 결혼한 지 5년이 되었습니다.
They both have day jobs.
둘 다 낮에 일을 합니다.
He found out
그는 알아냈다
that she was dating a co-worker.
그녀가 직장 동료와 사귀고 있었다는 것입니다.
They fight almost every day,
거의 매일 싸우고,
and they don't solve anything.
그리고 그들은 아무것도 해결하지 못합니다.
See?
보다?
They are now in "disconnect" mode.
이제 "연결 끊기" 모드에 있습니다.
I see.
알겠어요.
Next to them,
그 옆에는
that man supported someone,
그 사람은 누군가를 지지했고,
He lost everything and is now broke.
그는 모든 것을 잃었고 지금은 파산했습니다.
He even lost the house.
심지어 그는 집을 잃었습니다.
What can you do?
당신은 무엇을 할 수 있나요?
- How terrible. - TRUE.
- 정말 끔찍해요. - 진실.
It is.
그것은.
The people there,
거기 사람들은,
Do you also have stories like that?
당신에게도 그런 이야기가 있나요?
Exact.
정확한.
You try it.
당신은 그것을 시도합니다.
That? Try what?
저것? 무엇을 시도할까요?
Try it.
시도해 보세요.
Clear.
분명한.
Let's go...
가자...
No...
아니...
I can't do that.
나는 그렇게 할 수 없습니다.
Just say something.
그냥 말해보세요.
Anything works.
무엇이든 작동합니다.
That guy
그 사람
is a public official who does office work.
공무원이다 사무직을 하는 사람.
Yes.
예.
Recently,
최근에는
started to think
생각하기 시작했다
to retire earlier.
더 일찍 은퇴하려고.
In fact, he resigned.
실제로 그는 사임했습니다.
He wanted to spend more time with his wife.
그는 아내와 더 많은 시간을 보내고 싶었습니다.
but she
하지만 그녀는
had a serious accident
심각한 사고를 당했다
and lost an arm.
그리고 팔을 잃었습니다.
No!
아니요!
What an outrage.
정말 분노입니다.
After the accident,
사고 이후,
she stopped smiling.
그녀는 웃지 않았다.
I think she is convinced
내 생각엔 그녀가 확신하고 있는 것 같아
that there is no hope left.
희망이 남아 있지 않다는 것입니다.
He has been providing...
그는 지금까지...
your time,
당신의 시간,
your heart,
당신의 마음,
everything to her.
그녀의 모든 것.
But it's sold out.
그런데 매진이네요.
Sometimes you don't see the time
가끔 시간이 안맞는 경우가 있어요
for everything to end.
모든 것이 끝나도록.
Then he hates himself for thinking that.
그러면 그는 그런 생각을 하는 자신을 싫어합니다.
And the reason he traveled alone is...
그리고 그가 혼자 여행을 떠난 이유는...
Well...
음...
He doesn't appear to have anything on his arm.
팔에는 아무것도 없는 것 같습니다.
Sorry?
죄송합니다?
No one knows he uses a prosthetic arm.
그가 의수를 사용한다는 사실은 아무도 모릅니다.
His arm itches.
팔이 가렵다.
You still have the feeling that it is itchy.
여전히 가려운 느낌이 있습니다.
Did you write this for me to read?
내가 읽을 수 있도록 이 글을 쓰셨나요?
Sorry?
죄송합니다?
Don't you hear how it sounds?
무슨 소리인지 듣지 못하셨나요?
That is,
즉,
We have already passed the stage of stupidity.
우리는 이미 어리석음의 단계를 통과했습니다.
If you had used your phone
휴대폰을 사용했다면
or you would have tried a little,
아니면 조금이라도 시도해 봤을 텐데,
You wouldn't have delivered something like that.
당신은 그런 것을 배달하지 않았을 것입니다.
Do you know?
당신은 알고 있나요?
They all got jobs after graduating,
다들 일자리를 구했어 졸업 후,
but you came to university as if they had a great vocation.
그런데 넌 대학에 왔지 마치 그들이 훌륭한 소명을 갖고 있는 것처럼.
Honestly, I don't care.
솔직히, 나는 상관하지 않습니다.
Yeah?
응?
Do you care about your life and where you are going?
당신은 당신의 삶과 어디로 가는지에 관심이 있습니까?
If you cared, you wouldn't do this.
신경썼다면 이런 짓은 안 했을 텐데.
But to your poor parents They must care a lot.
하지만 가난한 부모님에게 그들은 많은 관심을 가져야 합니다.
Heavens...
천국...
you have no idea that the only one who ruins your life is you.
당신은 전혀 모른다 당신의 인생을 망치는 사람은 당신 뿐이라는 것을.
Poor.
가난한.
He's an idiot,
그 사람은 바보야
Now you're bringing my parents into this?
이제 내 부모님을 이 일에 참여시키려는 겁니까?
Who does he think he is?
그는 자신이 누구라고 생각합니까?
Why don't you say it to his face?
그 사람 얼굴에 대고 말하지 그래?
This is disrespectful. It is abuse of power by the teacher.
이것은 무례한 일입니다. 교사의 직권남용입니다.
And?
그리고?
Are you going to sue him?
그 사람을 고소할 거예요?
No.
아니요.
I will rewrite it and send it to you again.
다시 작성해서 보내드리겠습니다.
Good.
좋은.
When will I meet your boyfriend?
내가 네 남자친구를 언제 만날까?
Why now?
왜 지금?
Shouldn't they make it public now?
이제 공개하면 안되는거 아닌가요?
They had to make it official with everyone.
그들은 그것을 모든 사람에게 공식적으로 알려야 했습니다.
Now they live together.
이제 그들은 함께 산다.
I already told you that we are not living together.
우리는 함께 살지 않는다고 이미 말했어요.
Aren't you going out?
밖에 안 나가요?
Answer.
답변.
Hello, Do Hyun.
안녕하세요, 도현님.
You're done, right?
끝났죠?
What are we doing for dinner?
우리 저녁 먹으러 뭐 해요?
For dinner?
저녁 식사로?
Hyeong Jun will do dakbokkeumtang.
형준이가 닭볶음탕을 할 거예요.
What do you think?
어떻게 생각하나요?
- Excuse me? - No, he...
- 실례합니다 - 아니, 그 사람은...
Let's eat together!
같이 먹자!
- Hey. - I'd love to.
- 여기요. - 그러고 싶습니다.
Alright?
괜찮은?
Don't feel pressured to accept.
받아들여야 한다는 압박감을 느끼지 마세요.
He's not a very good cook.
그는 요리를 아주 잘하는 사람은 아닙니다.
Lee Yeon, Ian,
이연, 이안,
come eat
와서 먹어
Jun Kyung hasn't dated anyone in years.
준경은 수년간 누구와도 데이트를 하지 않았습니다.
Sometimes she feels like she is our oldest daughter,
가끔은 자기가 우리 큰딸 같다는 생각이 들 때도 있고,
so I'm very happy.
그래서 나는 매우 행복합니다.
So you make music.
그래서 당신은 음악을 만듭니다.
Yes.
예.
What kind of music do you make?
어떤 종류의 음악을 만드나요?
I don't stick to a specific genre.
저는 특정 장르를 고집하지 않아요.
So, do you busk?
그럼 버스킹을 하시나요?
Well...
음...
I compose music for films and videos.
저는 영화와 비디오를 위한 음악을 작곡합니다.
For videos.
비디오용.
Something we can recognize?
우리가 알아볼 수 있는 게 있나요?
Tell us what you have done.
당신이 한 일을 알려주십시오.
Anything you know?
아는 게 있나요?
Well...
음...
It doesn't have to be famous.
꼭 유명할 필요는 없습니다.
Tell us anything you've done. We will look for it.
당신이 한 일을 알려주세요. 우리는 그것을 찾아볼 것입니다.
Let's see...
어디 보자 ...
how about this one?
이건 어때요?
Let's see if you know him.
당신이 그를 아는지 봅시다.
I know him.
나는 그를 안다.
This one has animals, right?
이거 동물이 있는 거 맞죠?
They just met. How come they are already such friends?
그들은 방금 만났습니다. 왜 그들은 이미 그런 친구입니까?
Look at you.
당신을보세요.
That?
저것?
They barely know each other.
그들은 서로를 거의 알지 못합니다.
Do you like it that much?
그렇게 좋아해요?
Yes I like it.
네, 좋아요.
Maybe I got too excited.
어쩌면 내가 너무 흥분했는지도 모른다.
It's not that attractive
그다지 매력적이진 않네요
nor does he have a statuesque physique.
또한 그는 조각상 같은 체격도 없습니다.
So what did you see in him?
그럼 당신은 그에게서 무엇을 보았나요?
Why does our worldly and cold Jun Kyung
우리 세속적이고 차가운 준경이 왜
fell exhausted?
지쳤어?
Just because.
으니까.
Just because?
으니까?
Yeah.
응.
I like it.
좋아요.
Have a good trip.
좋은 여행 되세요.
- I close the door. - Bye bye.
- 문을 닫습니다. - 안녕.
Hyeong Jun.
현준.
You remember what I said, right?
내가 한 말 기억하지?
Yes, I remember.
네, 기억해요.
Goodbye, Jun Kyung.
안녕, 준경아.
Bye bye.
안녕.
Goodbye, Do Hyun.
안녕, 도현아.
So?
그래서?
I am opposed to this relationship.
나는 이 관계에 반대한다.
Because?
왜냐하면?
You got along well with Do Hyun.
도현이랑 잘 지내요.
He's too good for her,
그 사람은 그녀에게 너무 좋은 사람이에요
It's a waste that he's with Jun Kyung.
준경이랑 같이 있는 게 아깝다.
Honestly, I don't like it either.
솔직히 나도 싫다.
Because?
왜냐하면?
Because now,
왜냐면 지금은,
When something fun happens,
즐거운 일이 생기면,
He'll tell Do Hyun first, not me.
내가 아니라 그 사람이 도현에게 먼저 말할 거예요.
And when things go wrong, will lean on Do Hyun.
그리고 일이 잘못되면 도현에게 의지하겠습니다.
To be honest,
솔직히 말하자면
I was afraid.
두려웠어요.
About what?
무엇에 대해?
Not fitting in with someone like him
그 사람 같은 사람이랑은 어울리지 않아
or that he didn't want to fit in with me.
아니면 그가 나와 어울리고 싶지 않았다는 것입니다.
Haven't I changed much?
나 많이 변한거 아니야?
No.
아니요.
You've always been like this.
당신은 항상 이랬어요.
You just went back to being Seo Jun Kyung.
방금 서준경으로 돌아왔습니다.
Oh really?
오, 진짜?
What are you doing?
뭐하세요?
You haven't even changed.
당신은 하나도 변하지 않았습니다.
It's time to sleep, and I'm getting drunk.
이제 잠잘 시간이야, 그리고 난 취해가고 있어.
I think I got too excited today.
오늘은 너무 흥분한 것 같아요.
I think today will stay with me for a while.
오늘은 한동안 나와 함께 있을 것 같아요.
It was such a good day
정말 좋은 날이었어
that I almost feel like I don't deserve it.
나는 그럴 자격이 거의 없다고 느낀다.
In fact...
사실...
My mom passed away recently.
최근에 엄마가 돌아가셨어요.
I'm sorry, I didn't know.
미안해요. 몰랐어요.
I look a lot like my mom.
나는 엄마와 많이 닮았습니다.
But, in recent times,
그러나 최근에는
we get to feel
우리는 느끼게 된다
a great resentment.
굉장한 분노입니다.
I couldn't even tell him
나는 그에게 말할 수도 없었다.
that I felt it.
내가 느꼈던 것.
We did not reconcile.
우리는 화해하지 않았습니다.
She left.
그녀는 떠났다.
Even if you never told him...
그 사람에게 말하지 않았더라도...
just the fact of having...
단지 가지고 있다는 사실...
that feeling,
그 느낌,
your mother
너의 어머니
I would definitely tell you...
나는 분명히 당신에게 말할 것입니다 ...
which is fine.
괜찮습니다.
What is the day you remember most in your life?
인생에서 가장 기억에 남는 날은 언제인가요?
- That? - Except the day we met.
- 저것? - 우리가 만난 날 빼고요.
Well...
음...
The day I remember most...
가장 기억에 남는 날..
It's the day my son was born.
내 아들이 태어난 날이에요.